<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Your awesome title</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 14:12:58 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 14:12:58 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the author: Ann Cleeves</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/featured/featured-ann-cleeves.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ann Cleeves book cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ann Cleeves is a British crime-writer who needs little introduction. In 2006 she won the inaugural Duncan Lawrie Dagger, the richest crime-writing prize in the world, for her novel &lt;cite&gt;Raven Black&lt;/cite&gt;. Ann also created the Vera Stanhope novels which have been dramatised as the TV detective series &lt;cite&gt;Vera&lt;/cite&gt; and the Jimmy Perez novels as the series &lt;cite&gt;Shetland&lt;/cite&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why do you think crime books are so popular?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think crime novels have always been popular and now we have a greater variety than ever. The popularity has something to do with great story-telling and the sense of resolution at the end of the novel. There are books to suit every possible taste from the gentle and domestic to pacy thrillers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who were your literary influences as you were growing up?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was an Enid Blyton child; though I realised quite soon that she wasn’t a fantastic writer there was something very compulsive about her books. She had the skill to make the reader long to turn the page to find out what would happen next. I moved on quite quickly through Malcolm Saville, the Father Brown and Sherlock Holmes stories to Christie and the rest of the Golden Age detective novelists. Although I went on to read widely in very different genres, crime fiction was always my comfort reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where did the character of Vera Stanhope come from?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vera appeared fully formed when I was stuck with the plot of &lt;cite&gt;The Crow Trap&lt;/cite&gt;. It was planned as a novel of psychological suspense and I didn’t expect to create a detective character at all. Trying to unpick it, I think Vera was inspired by some of the formidable spinsters I knew when I was growing up. I was born in the mid-fifties and they were probably created by the war - they’d either lost sweethearts to the fighting or they’d taken on responsibilities that wouldn’t have been available to them in previous times. They seemed to rule the small town where I lived - one was a hospital matron, another the Sunday school teacher, another the head mistress of my infant school. They were very competent, but not at all glamorous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You must have had your own idea of what your characters look like. Has it helped or hindered you having them live on screen?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to keep the screen characters separate from the characters in my head - though Brenda Blethyn has very much become my Vera.  It’s easier with Jimmy Perez, the detective in &lt;cite&gt;Shetland&lt;/cite&gt;, because Dougie Henshall looks quite different from my creation. He’s blond and Scottish while my Jimmy is dark and Spanish-looking. Dougie absolutely captures the essence of the man, though. I’ve been incredibly lucky with both adaptations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you still read other crime writers now you are a writer yourself?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Absolutely! My reading passion is translated crime fiction. I love the French writer Fred Vargas and I’ve just come across Valerio Varesi who sets his work in the Pau valley in Italy. And of course there are some wonderful Icelandic and Scandinavian authors when I’m in the mood for cold weather and a bleak landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you know when an idea has the potential to become a book?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know really until I start writing about it. I never plot in advance and the story grows. I’m influenced by my preoccupations of the time rather than a specific idea. The theme emerges as I write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything you can share about your latest project?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My new book, &lt;cite&gt;Cold Earth&lt;/cite&gt;, will be published in October. It’s a &lt;cite&gt;Shetland&lt;/cite&gt; novel. There’s a landslide that cuts Shetland mainland in half, sweeping away a small croft house as mud and rocks slip towards the sea. Everyone believes that the house was empty, but the body of a woman wearing a red silk dress is found in the debris. I’ve just started a new Vera book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What would be your perfect day?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up early to write - I still love the process of making up stories. Then a walk up the Northumberland coast with my husband Tim, perhaps with lunch at the Boat Shed in Amble. And we’d end up in the Rockcliffe Arms, our local pub, with our friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/19504702?QRY=CAUBIB%3C%20IRN(4807)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Cleeves%2C%20Ann&quot;&gt;Reserve books by Ann Cleeves from our libraries.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 09:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/meet-the-author-ann-cleeves/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/meet-the-author-ann-cleeves/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the author: Bernard Cornwell</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/featured/featured-bernard-cornwell.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bernard Cornwell book cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bernard Cornwell, OBE is an English author of historical novels. Two of his historical novel series have been adapted for television; the &lt;cite&gt;Sharpe&lt;/cite&gt; series by ITV and &lt;cite&gt;The Last Kingdom&lt;/cite&gt; by BBC. In 2014 he published a nonfiction book, &lt;cite&gt;Waterloo: The History of Four Days, Three Armies and Three Battles&lt;/cite&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where did your interest in history and particularly military history come from? Did you have an inspiring history teacher at school?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had an inspiring English teacher at school, but the only history teacher I can recall was rather dour. I suspect my interest in history was inherited! When I was in my 50’s I met my birth mother for the first time and found her flat crammed with historical novels… so make of that what you will. I don’t remember a time when I wasn’t obsessed by history, from a child it was my favourite reading and I cycled miles to visit old churches, ruins, whatever. As for military history, I was adopted into a family of fundamentalist puritans, belonging to a sect called The Peculiar People (really!) and among the many things of which they disapproved was anything to do with the military so, naturally, I became fascinated by all things military.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**Where did the character of Uhtred come from? **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He has some basis in history – there was a family that frequently used the name Uhtred in the 8th, 9th and 10th centuries, and they were the owners of Bebbanburg, now Bamburgh Castle. My Uhtred is fictional, but I discovered the family by meeting my natural father, again when I was in my 50’s, and discovered that he was a direct descendant of that family. The surname had changed over the years to Oughtred, but his family tree (and mine) went all the way back to the Anglo-Saxon period. My curiosity was aroused by their holding onto Bebbanburg – a Saxon and Christian enclave in a Danish and pagan kingdom of Northumbria. I suspect they collaborated, but we don’t really know. Whatever, Uhtred is one of my ancestors!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you write are you a planner or do you get ideas of where to take the story as you write it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t have an outline. Some writers plot very carefully, and their books are great, but others, like me, leave it to instinct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you get much time for leisure reading or is it all research?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read a lot, and a lot that has nothing to do with history, though I suppose about half my reading is somehow connected to whatever period I’m writing about. I do like a well-written thriller – I’m a great fan of John Sandford – but mostly I read non-fiction. I’ve just finished &lt;cite&gt;Our Man in Charleston&lt;/cite&gt; by Christopher Dickey, a splendid book about the British consul in Charleston, South Carolina, during the American Civil War, which I read mainly because he lived a few houses away from mine in that city. And I’ve just started &lt;cite&gt;The Incredible Unlikeliness of Being&lt;/cite&gt; by Alice Roberts, and am loving it so far!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything you can share about your latest project?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest one, finished yesterday, is the 10th novel about Uhtred and, at last, he makes a proper attempt to recapture Bebbanburg. But will he succeed? I ain’t saying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Given a time machine and the ability to go backwards or forwards what date would you set the clock for and why? (assuming you could get back..)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be nice to meet Nell Gwynne? And if you did, why come back? But I suppose if I was forced to make a choice I think I’d want to be in the Globe for the first performance of, well, almost anything! I’ll choose &lt;cite&gt;The Tempest&lt;/cite&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/15350086?QRY=CAUBIB%3C%20IRN(3276)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Cornwell%2C%20Bernard&quot;&gt;Reserve Bernard Cornwell’s books from our libraries.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 11:29:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/meet-the-author-bernard-cornwell/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/meet-the-author-bernard-cornwell/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Brave New Reads 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/featured/featured-brave-new-reads-2016.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Brave New Reads 2016 logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citespill-simmer-falter-withercite-by-sara-baumehttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq13675190qryctibib3c20irn53434335ampqrytextspill20simmer20falter20wither&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/13675190?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(53434335)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Spill%20simmer%20falter%20wither&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Spill Simmer Falter Wither&lt;/cite&gt; by Sara Baume&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/13675190?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(53434335)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Spill%20simmer%20falter%20wither&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/spill-simmer-falter-wither.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Spill Simmer Falter Wither by Sara Baume&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Springtime, and two misfits – one an eccentric loner and the other a one-eyed dog – forge an unlikely relationship. In a tired seaside town, these outcasts find solace in each other. But as their friendship grows, they are driven away by a community that perceives menace where there is only mishap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://suffolklibraries.lib.overdrive.com/AE51566C-D2D5-406C-9AC0-ECEA9C3F3E96/10/50/en/ContentDetails.htm?id=BF5B1A8C-71FF-496C-9947-E617A9F9EE83&quot;&gt;Borrow &lt;cite&gt;Spill Simmer Falter Wither&lt;/cite&gt; by Sara Baume as an eBook on Overdrive.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citesigns-preceding-the-end-of-the-worldcite-by-yuri-herrerahttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq13675608qryctibib3c20irn46866889ampqrytextsigns20preceding20the20end20of20the20world&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/13675608?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(46866889)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Signs%20preceding%20the%20end%20of%20the%20world&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Signs Preceding the End of the World&lt;/cite&gt; by Yuri Herrera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/13675608?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(46866889)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Signs%20preceding%20the%20end%20of%20the%20world&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/signs-preceding-the-end-of-the-world.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Signs Preceding the End of the World by Yuri Herrera&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yuri Herrera explores the crossings and translations people make in their minds and language as they move from one country to another, especially when there’s no going back. Traversing this lonely territory is Makina; leaving behind her life in Mexico to search for her brother, she is smuggled into the USA carrying a pair of secret messages – one from her mother and one from the Mexican underworld.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://suffolklibraries.lib.overdrive.com/AE51566C-D2D5-406C-9AC0-ECEA9C3F3E96/10/50/en/ContentDetails.htm?id=7DFD48C2-FB7C-433E-A11F-B1D43C772088&quot;&gt;Borrow &lt;cite&gt;Signs Preceding the End of the World&lt;/cite&gt; by Yuri Herrera as an eBook on Overdrive.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citethe-last-pilotcite-by-benjamin-johncockhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq13675988qryctibib3c20irn49013453ampqrytextthe20last20pilot&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/13675988?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(49013453)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20last%20pilot&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The Last Pilot&lt;/cite&gt; by Benjamin Johncock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/13675988?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(49013453)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20last%20pilot&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/the-last-pilot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Last Pilot by Benjamin Johncock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the 1960s, the space race is underway and test pilot Jim Harrison and his colleagues are offered a place in history as the world’s first astronauts. But when his young family is thrown into crisis, Jim is faced with a decision that will affect the course of the rest of his life – whether to accept his ticket to the moon, and at what cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://suffolklibraries.lib.overdrive.com/AE51566C-D2D5-406C-9AC0-ECEA9C3F3E96/10/50/en/ContentDetails.htm?id=7864D4AC-3D65-44B1-BEA9-44F9DDCF50AA&quot;&gt;Borrow &lt;cite&gt;The Last Pilot&lt;/cite&gt; by Benjamin Johncock as an eBook on Overdrive.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citethe-secret-to-not-drowningcite-by-colette-snowdenhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq13676397qryctibib3c20irn52717751ampqrytextthe20secret20to20not20drowning&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/13676397?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(52717751)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20secret%20to%20not%20drowning&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The Secret to Not Drowning&lt;/cite&gt; by Colette Snowden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/13676397?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(52717751)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20secret%20to%20not%20drowning&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/the-secret-to-not-drowning.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Secret to Not Drowning by Colette Snowden&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did the girl who once dreamed of being a Charlie’s Angel become such a cowed and submissive woman? Marion’s life appears perfectly fine but she is controlled and bullied by her husband, her only respite a once a week trip to the local swimming pool. A chance meeting with an old school-friend develops into a secret relationship. She could leave her abusive and unfaithful husband. But is it too late?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://suffolklibraries.lib.overdrive.com/AE51566C-D2D5-406C-9AC0-ECEA9C3F3E96/10/50/en/ContentDetails.htm?id=0E0B03E7-CEDF-415E-BC07-35A7516E4F83&quot;&gt;Borrow &lt;cite&gt;The Secret to Not Drowning&lt;/cite&gt; by Colette Snowden as an eBook on Overdrive.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citejust-mercycite-by-bryan-stevensonhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq13676975qryctibib3c20irn45907290ampqrytextjust20mercy203a20a20story20of20justice20and20redemption&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/13676975?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(45907290)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Just%20mercy%20%3A%20a%20story%20of%20justice%20and%20redemption&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Just Mercy&lt;/cite&gt; by Bryan Stevenson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/13676975?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(45907290)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Just%20mercy%20%3A%20a%20story%20of%20justice%20and%20redemption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/just-mercy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Just Mercy by Bryan Stevenson&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bryan Stevenson was a young lawyer when he founded the Equal Justice Initiative, a legal practice dedicated to defending those most desperate and in need: the poor, the wrongly condemned, and women and children trapped in the farthest reaches of our criminal justice system. &lt;cite&gt;Just Mercy&lt;/cite&gt; is at once an unforgettable account of an idealistic, gifted young lawyer’s coming of age, a moving window into the lives of those he has defended, and an inspiring argument for compassion in the pursuit of justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://suffolklibraries.lib.overdrive.com/AE51566C-D2D5-406C-9AC0-ECEA9C3F3E96/10/50/en/ContentDetails.htm?id=6FFBA7A8-D441-47FC-82B5-A8C0495109FC&quot;&gt;Borrow &lt;cite&gt;Just Mercy&lt;/cite&gt; by Bryan Stevenson as an eBook on Overdrive.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citethe-illusion-of-separatenesscite-by-simon-van-booyhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq13677393qryctibib3c20irn22123678ampqrytextthe20illusion20of20separateness&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/13677393?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(22123678)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20illusion%20of%20separateness&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The Illusion of Separateness&lt;/cite&gt; by Simon Van Booy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/13677393?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(22123678)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20illusion%20of%20separateness&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/the-illusion-of-separateness.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Illusion of Separateness by Simon Van Booy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story of how one man’s act of mercy on a World War II battlefield changes the lives of six strangers across time and place, including a child on the brink of starvation, a blind museum curator looking for love, a German infantryman, and a humble caretaker at a retirement home in Santa Monica. These characters remain unaware of their connection until seemingly random acts of selflessness reveal the vital parts they play in each other’s lives. Inspired by true events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://suffolklibraries.lib.overdrive.com/AE51566C-D2D5-406C-9AC0-ECEA9C3F3E96/10/50/en/ContentDetails.htm?id=65E02645-E949-44DF-B6CB-119EBD3DF24F&quot;&gt;Borrow &lt;cite&gt;The Illusion of Separateness&lt;/cite&gt; by Simon Van Booy as an eBook on Overdrive.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 10:46:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/new-suggestions/fiction/brave-new-reads-2016/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/new-suggestions/fiction/brave-new-reads-2016/</guid>
        
        
        <category>new-suggestions</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New children’s books for April 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/featured/featured-tidy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tidy by Emily Gravett&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;picture-books-and-board-books&quot;&gt;Picture books and board books&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citecaptain-jack-and-the-piratescite-by-peter-bently-and-helen-oxenburyhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq12441422qryctibib3c20irn50447864ampqrytextcaptain20jack20and20the20pirates&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/12441422?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(50447864)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Captain%20Jack%20and%20the%20pirates&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Captain Jack and the pirates&lt;/cite&gt; by Peter Bently and Helen Oxenbury&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/12441422?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(50447864)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Captain%20Jack%20and%20the%20pirates&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/captain-jack-and-the-pirates.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Captain Jack and the pirates by Peter Bently and Helen Oxenbury&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This roll-along rhyme set on a sandy beach and starring two little boys and a baby, is tenderly enhanced by Helen Oxenbury’s beautiful illustrations. It’s a pleasure to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citethe-perfect-picniccite-by-ciara-floodhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq12442364qryctibib3c20irn573959ampqrytextthe20perfect20picnic&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/12442364?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(573959)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20perfect%20picnic&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The perfect picnic&lt;/cite&gt; by Ciara Flood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/12442364?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(573959)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20perfect%20picnic&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/the-perfect-picnic.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The perfect picnic by Ciara Flood&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like detailed illustrations of domestic interiors in a hedgerow sort-of-a-way (think Brambly Hedge), and delicious drawings of picnic food (think Lighthouse Keeper’s Lunch), then you might like to pore over the pictures in this book. It’s about a poor old long suffering mole and a demanding, flighty squirrel (in an Alison Uttley sort-of-a-way) and it’s just lovely to read to young children. Ciara Flood’s first book Those Pesky rabbits, came out last year, and that’s a joy too. Roll on book number 3!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citetidycite-by-emily-gravetthttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq12443347qryctibib3c20irn60138660ampqrytexttidy&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/12443347?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(60138660)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Tidy&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Tidy&lt;/cite&gt; by Emily Gravett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/12443347?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(60138660)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Tidy&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/tidy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tidy by Emily Gravett&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cautionary tale with all the wit and brilliant artistry we’ve come to expect from Emily Gravett. Her hero this time is an OCD badger called Bill, who battle against the anarchy of nature leads to deforestation and flooding. I wonder if someone will pass a copy to the Environment Agency? She is one clever cookie that Emily G!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citei-went-to-the-supermarketcite-by-paul-howardhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq12443675qryctibib3c20irn58865843ampqrytexti20went20to20the20supermarket&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/12443675?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(58865843)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=I%20went%20to%20the%20supermarket&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;I went to the supermarket&lt;/cite&gt; by Paul Howard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/12443675?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(58865843)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=I%20went%20to%20the%20supermarket&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/i-went-to-the-supermarket.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;I went to the supermarket by Paul Howard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A brother and sister play the traditional memory game in this fun-filled picture book, competing to add the most outrageous items to their shopping lists. I love the contrast between their choices, the expressions on the faces of the children and the creatures they introduce, the way the little girl prefaces every sentence with “Well”, and the surprise ending. A good choice for story time at playgroups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citenibbles-the-book-monstercite-by-emma-yarletthttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq12448049qryctibib3c20irn63183236ampqrytextnibbles203a20the20book20monster&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/12448049?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(63183236)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Nibbles%20%3A%20the%20book%20monster&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Nibbles: The book monster&lt;/cite&gt; by Emma Yarlett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/12448049?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(63183236)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Nibbles%20%3A%20the%20book%20monster&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/nibbles-the-book-monster.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nibbles: The book monster by Emma Yarlett&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nibbles looks like an emoticon with teeth, but there the similarity with digital format ends. This is an astonishing book about a voracious little creature who eats his way through several traditional stories. Emma Yarlett must have worked for months to create such stunning paper engineering, and we are the lucky beneficiaries of her creativity. Wow what a book!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;junior-novels&quot;&gt;Junior novels&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citesputniks-guide-to-life-on-earthcite-by-frank-cottrell-boycehttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq12461499qryctibib3c20irn63356364ampqrytextsputnik27s20guide20to20life20on20earth&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/12461499?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(63356364)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Sputnik%27s%20guide%20to%20life%20on%20Earth&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Sputnik’s guide to life on earth&lt;/cite&gt; by Frank Cottrell Boyce&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/12461499?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(63356364)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Sputnik%27s%20guide%20to%20life%20on%20Earth&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/sputniks-guide-to-life-on-earth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sputnik’s guide to life on earth by Frank Cottrell Boyce&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Frank Cottrell Boyce uses the sad story of Laika the dog, the first living creature in space, as inspiration for a novel about the importance of home”. Prez Mellows’ grandfather has dementia, and Prez, who hasn’t talked since his grandfather was taken away, is spending the summer with a temporary foster family. When he answers the door to Sputnik, a mind-reading alien, the rest of the family, just see a cute dog whom they welcome into their home. Prez and Sputnik spend an amazing summer saving the world, (and cutting hair with lightsabres!) and Prez is eventually reunited with his grandfather. It’s a poignant touching tale, but as with all the books by this marvellous author, it’s just plain funny. It’s easy to read too, and happily enhanced by Steven Lenton’s illustrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;junior-non-fiction&quot;&gt;Junior non-fiction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citeeat-your-greens-reds-yellows-and-purplescite-by-james-mitchem-and-carrie-lovehttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq12460670qryctibib3c20irn60138303ampqrytexteat20your20greens2c20reds2c20yellows20and20purples&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/12460670?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(60138303)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Eat%20your%20greens%2C%20reds%2C%20yellows%20and%20purples&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Eat your greens, reds, yellows and purples&lt;/cite&gt; by James Mitchem and Carrie Love&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/12460670?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(60138303)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Eat%20your%20greens%2C%20reds%2C%20yellows%20and%20purples&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/eat-your-greens-reds-yellows-and-purples.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Eat your greens, reds, yellows and purples by James Mitchem and Carrie Love&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This super cookery book has bright colourful photographs, with clear captions and well written instructions for delicious looking vegetarian recipes. If only the type face were thicker, it would be just perfect and we’d buy even more copies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;young-teen&quot;&gt;Young teen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citea-seven-letter-wordcite-by-kim-slaterhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq12457398qryctibib3c20irn58865295ampqrytexta20seven20letter20word&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/12457398?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(58865295)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=A%20seven%20letter%20word&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;A seven letter word&lt;/cite&gt; by Kim Slater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/12457398?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(58865295)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=A%20seven%20letter%20word&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/a-seven-letter-word.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A seven letter word by Kim Slater&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a page-turner of a book about an intelligent articulate boy who developed a stutter after his mother’s sudden disappearance. And stutter is the 7 letter word of the title. Finlay hates the word and his stutter, which has made him an easy target for bullies. Scrabble is how he pours out his thoughts to his missing mum, and Scrabble rules head each new chapter. However a new friend he meets at a Scrabble tournament, and the belief that he can find his mother, change his life. Kim Slater was shortlisted for the Waterstone’s Children’s Book Prize last year for Smart, her debut novel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citehead-over-heelscite-by-holly-smalehttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq12458243qryctibib3c20irn9437ampqrytexthead20over20heels&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/12458243?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(9437)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Head%20over%20heels&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Head over heels&lt;/cite&gt; by Holly Smale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/12458243?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(9437)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Head%20over%20heels&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/head-over-heels.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Head over heels by Holly Smale&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the 5th title in the Geek Girl series, about Harriet Manners, the girl whose head is filled with useful facts and helpful suggestions, and we think her fans will love it. Poor old Harriet just can’t resist organising every detail of her friends lives for them, but this time, much to her astonishment, some of them resist. She’s been so busy organising them and using her baby step-sister as a fashion prop, that she almost misses the boy who has fallen in love with her. (Now I would love her to organise my life, it sounds like heaven!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citedesolationcite-by-derek-landyhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq12455718qryctibib3c20irn766511ampqrytextdesolation&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/12455718?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(766511)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Desolation&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Desolation&lt;/cite&gt; by Derek Landy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/12455718?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(766511)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Desolation&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/desolation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Desolation by Derek Landy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the second title in the Demon Road trilogy “Reeling from their bloody encounter in New York City, Amber and Milo flee north. On their trail are the Hounds of Hell - five demonic bikers who will stop at nothing to drag their quarries back to their unholy master.” NB All Landy fans, American Monsters (the final instalment) is due to be published on 25 August, but if it’s as fat as Desolation, you may want to borrow it in digital format too – so much lighter to pack!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 10:29:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/new-suggestions/childrens-ya-books/new-childrens-books-for-may-2016/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/new-suggestions/childrens-ya-books/new-childrens-books-for-may-2016/</guid>
        
        
        <category>new-suggestions</category>
        
        <category>childrens-ya-books</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New music for May 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/featured/featured-fallen-angels.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fallen angels by Bob Dylan&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citefallen-angelscite-by-bob-dylanhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq15250463qrycaubib3c20irn203217ampqrytextdylan2c20bob2c201941-&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/15250463?QRY=CAUBIB%3C%20IRN(203217)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Dylan%2C%20Bob%2C%201941-&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Fallen angels&lt;/cite&gt; by Bob Dylan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/15250463?QRY=CAUBIB%3C%20IRN(203217)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Dylan%2C%20Bob%2C%201941-&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/fallen-angels.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fallen angels by Bob Dylan&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bob Dylan follows &lt;cite&gt;Shadows in the Night&lt;/cite&gt; with his 37th studio album. This one draws on the tunes of some of America’s greatest songwriters including Johnny Mercer, Sammy Cahn and Harold Arlen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citethese-peoplecite-by-richard-ashcrofthttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq15252842qrycaubib3c20irn9705601ampqrytextashcroft2c20richard2c201971-&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/15252842?QRY=CAUBIB%3C%20IRN(9705601)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Ashcroft%2C%20Richard%2C%201971-&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;These people&lt;/cite&gt; by Richard Ashcroft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/15252842?QRY=CAUBIB%3C%20IRN(9705601)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Ashcroft%2C%20Richard%2C%201971-&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/these-people.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;These people by Richard Ashcroft&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fourth solo album from The Verve lead singer. &lt;cite&gt;These People&lt;/cite&gt; is the first new album in six years from the Brit and Ivor Novello award winning artist. It was produced by Ashcroft and marks a reunion with Wil Malone, who worked on the string arrangements on The Verve’s &lt;cite&gt;A Northern Soul&lt;/cite&gt; (1995), &lt;cite&gt;Urban Hymns&lt;/cite&gt; (1997), and the platinum-selling debut solo album &lt;cite&gt;Alone with Everybody&lt;/cite&gt; (2000).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citei-still-docite-by-eric-claptonhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq15257284qrycaubib3c20irn176474qrytextclapton2c20eric&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/15257284?QRY=CAUBIB%3C%20IRN(176474)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Clapton%2C%20Eric&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;I still do&lt;/cite&gt; by Eric Clapton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/15257284?QRY=CAUBIB%3C%20IRN(176474)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Clapton%2C%20Eric&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/i-still-do.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;I still do by Eric Clapton&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;23rd solo album from Eric Clapton. This one features a combination of new material as well as cover versions of classic songs, contemporary tunes and influences Clapton has interpreted in his own style. It also features the track &lt;cite&gt;I will be there&lt;/cite&gt; featuring one “Angelo Mysterioso” who may or may not be George Harrison according to speculation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citethe-ridecite-by-catfish-amp-the-bottlemenhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq15259293qrycaubib3c20irn25346706qrytextcatfish20and20the20bottlemen&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/15259293?QRY=CAUBIB%3C%20IRN(25346706)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Catfish%20and%20The%20Bottlemen&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The ride&lt;/cite&gt; by Catfish &amp;amp; the Bottlemen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/15259293?QRY=CAUBIB%3C%20IRN(25346706)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Catfish%20and%20The%20Bottlemen&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/the-ride.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The ride by Catfish &amp;amp; the Bottlemen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The indie heroes return with the follow-up to their massive-selling debut, &lt;cite&gt;The Balcony&lt;/cite&gt;. They say their album consists of songs that were ‘made to play live’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citeelectronica-2cite-by-jean-michel-jarrehttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq15260241qrycaubib3c20irn1684745qrytextjarre2c20jean-michel&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/15260241?QRY=CAUBIB%3C%20IRN(1684745)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Jarre%2C%20Jean-Michel&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Electronica 2&lt;/cite&gt; by Jean Michel Jarre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/15260241?QRY=CAUBIB%3C%20IRN(1684745)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Jarre%2C%20Jean-Michel&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/electronica-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Electronica 2 by Jean Michel Jarre&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second part of the two-part album based around collaborations with other electronic musicians from a wide range of decades and styles. This one features contributions from Pet Shop Boys, Primal Scream and Gary Numan amongst others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citekidstickscite-by-beth-ortonhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq15261542qrycaubib3c20irn1803751qrytextorton2c20beth&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/15261542?QRY=CAUBIB%3C%20IRN(1803751)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Orton%2C%20Beth&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Kidsticks&lt;/cite&gt; by Beth Orton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/15261542?QRY=CAUBIB%3C%20IRN(1803751)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Orton%2C%20Beth&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/kidsticks.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kidsticks by Beth Orton&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is always great to have new material from Beth Orton. Four years after her last album Beth returns with more trippy electronics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citethe-heart-speaks-in-whisperscite-by-corinne-bailey-raehttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq15263514qrycaubib3c20irn1803921qrytextrae2c20corinne20bailey&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/15263514?QRY=CAUBIB%3C%20IRN(1803921)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Rae%2C%20Corinne%20Bailey&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The heart speaks in whispers&lt;/cite&gt; by Corinne Bailey Rae&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/15263514?QRY=CAUBIB%3C%20IRN(1803921)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Rae%2C%20Corinne%20Bailey&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/the-heart-speaks-in-whispers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The heart speaks in whispers by Corinne Bailey Rae&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third album from CBR. This one “is about transformation and new life and confidence and joy” and finding beauty in life’s tragedies and triumphs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 10:26:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/new-suggestions/music/new-music-for-may-2016/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/new-suggestions/music/new-music-for-may-2016/</guid>
        
        
        <category>new-suggestions</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New non-fiction for May 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/featured/featured-dont-you-leave-me-here-my-life.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Don&#39;t you leave me here: my life by Wilko Johnson&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citedont-you-leave-me-here-my-lifecite-by-wilko-johnsonhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq8638783qryctibib3c20irn61025476qrytextdon27t20you20leave20me20here203a20my20life&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8638783?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(61025476)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Don%27t%20you%20leave%20me%20here%20%3A%20my%20life&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Don’t you leave me here: my life&lt;/cite&gt; by Wilko Johnson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8638783?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(61025476)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Don%27t%20you%20leave%20me%20here%20%3A%20my%20life&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/dont-you-leave-me-here-my-life.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Don&#39;t you leave me here: my life by Wilko Johnson&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2013, Dr Feelgood founder Wilko Johnson was diagnosed with terminal cancer. With ten months to live, he decided to accept his imminent death and went on the road. He recorded Going Back Home with Roger Daltrey and prepared for the worst. Then the strangest thing happened: he didn’t die. ‘Don’t You Leave Me Here’ is the story of his life in music, his life with cancer, and his life now - in the future he never thought he would see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citethe-private-lives-of-the-tudors-uncovering-the-hidden-secrets-of-britains-greatest-dynastycite-by-tracy-bormanhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq8647202qryctibib3c20irn61025484qrytextthe20private20lives20of20the20tudors203a20uncovering20the20hidden20secrets20of20britain27s20greatest20dynasty&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8647202?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(61025484)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20private%20lives%20of%20the%20Tudors%20%3A%20uncovering%20the%20hidden%20secrets%20of%20Britain%27s%20greatest%20dynasty&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The private lives of the Tudors: uncovering the hidden secrets of Britain’s greatest dynasty&lt;/cite&gt; by Tracy Borman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8647202?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(61025484)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20private%20lives%20of%20the%20Tudors%20%3A%20uncovering%20the%20hidden%20secrets%20of%20Britain%27s%20greatest%20dynasty&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/the-private-lives-of-the-tudors.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The private lives of the Tudors: uncovering the hidden secrets of Britain&#39;s greatest dynasty by Tracy Borman&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tudor monarchs were constantly surrounded by an army of attendants, courtiers and ministers. Even in their most private moments, they were accompanied by a servant specifically appointed for the task. A groom of the stool would stand patiently by as Henry VIII performed his daily purges, and when Elizabeth I retired for the evening, one of her female servants would sleep at the end of her bed. These attendants knew the truth behind the glamorous exterior and this book reveals the previously unexamined details about the characters we think we know so well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citepaul-mccartney-the-biographycite-by-philip-normanhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq21037272qryctibib3c20irn61025374qrytextpaul20mccartney203a20the20biography&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/21037272?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(61025374)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Paul%20McCartney%20%3A%20the%20biography&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Paul McCartney: the biography&lt;/cite&gt; by Philip Norman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/21037272?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(61025374)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Paul%20McCartney%20%3A%20the%20biography&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/paul-mccartney-the-biography.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Paul McCartney: the biography by Philip Norman&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book offers a first-hand, insider’s account of the life of a member of one of the most influential and widely-imitated band of all time, making this a fascinating fly-on-the-wall chronicle. Philip Norman has previously published definitive books on The Beatles and John Lennon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citeshut-up-legscite-by-jens-voigthttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq21039277qryctibib3c20irn64694958qrytextshut20up20legs&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/21039277?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(64694958)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Shut%20up%20legs!&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Shut up legs&lt;/cite&gt; by Jens Voigt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/21039277?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(64694958)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Shut%20up%20legs!&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/shut-up-legs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Shut up legs by Jens Voigt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even by the standards of a sport that requires enormous stamina and capacity for suffering, Jens Voigt is in a class on his own. Beloved by cycling fans for his madcap one-man breakaways as much as his sense of humour and quotable catchphrases, Jens is one of the most popular personalities in cycling. This book is a funny, insightful, and entertaining look at the tough realities of professional cycling, told in Jens’s trademark irreverent and inimitable style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citea-life-discarded-148-diaries-found-in-a-skipcite-by-alexander-mastershttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq8656410qryctibib3c20irn59112088qrytexta20life20discarded203a2014820diaries20found20in20a20skip&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8656410?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(59112088)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=A%20life%20discarded%20%3A%20148%20diaries%20found%20in%20a%20skip&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;A life discarded: 148 diaries found in a skip&lt;/cite&gt; by Alexander Masters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8656410?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(59112088)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=A%20life%20discarded%20%3A%20148%20diaries%20found%20in%20a%20skip&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/a-life-discarded.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A life discarded: 148 diaries found in a skip by Alexander Masters&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2001 Alexander and his friends found 148 journals discarded in a skip. This book describes Alexander’s attempts to unravel the mysterious writer of these journals – leading us into the oddly fascinating life of an entirely unremarkable person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citecheer-up-love-adventures-in-depression-with-the-crab-of-hatecite-by-susan-calmanhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq8659368qryctibib3c20irn61025629qrytextcheer20up20love203a20adventures20in20depression20with20the20crab20of20hate&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8659368?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(61025629)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Cheer%20up%20love%20%3A%20adventures%20in%20depression%20with%20the%20crab%20of%20hate&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Cheer up love: adventures in depression with the crab of hate&lt;/cite&gt; by Susan Calman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8659368?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(61025629)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Cheer%20up%20love%20%3A%20adventures%20in%20depression%20with%20the%20crab%20of%20hate&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/cheer-up-love.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cheer up love: adventures in depression with the crab of hate by Susan Calman&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Susan Calman will be familiar to listeners of The News Quiz on Radio 4. You may not know that she also suffers from depression. Despite being one of the funniest women in the UK she has had her own black dog, the Crab of Hate , whispering in her ear since she can remember. And her answer? To talk about it. A woman who measures the length of her depression by box sets (‘Cracker’ good, ‘West Wing’ bad) and who has made therapy more of a hobby than a medical requirement, Susan has written the book on what’s it’s like to be gloomy and enjoy it. Certain that the world needs people with a more cynical outlook on life, the book is a celebration of what she, and if statistics are to be believed, one in four of us, go through daily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citefirst-light-a-celebration-of-alan-garnercite-edited-by-erica-wagnerhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq8661694qryctibib3c20irn61024424qrytextfirst20light203a20a20celebration20of20alan20garner&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8661694?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(61024424)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=First%20light%20%3A%20a%20celebration%20of%20Alan%20Garner&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;First light: a celebration of Alan Garner&lt;/cite&gt; edited by Erica Wagner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8661694?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(61024424)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=First%20light%20%3A%20a%20celebration%20of%20Alan%20Garner&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/a-celebration-of-alan-garner.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;First light: a celebration of Alan Garner edited by Erica Wagner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more than 50 years, Alan Garner has enraptured generations of readers with works like The Weirdstone of Brisingamen , The Owl Service , Red Shift , and The Stone Book Quartet . Philip Pullman has described him as ‘the most important British writer of fantasy since Tolkien’. Alan Garner has inspired readers and writers alike. Now, to celebrate his 80th birthday, comes First Light. A collaboration by many of the acclaimed writers, artists, archaeologists and historians he has influenced over the years, this anthology includes original contributions from David Almond, Margaret Atwood, John Burnside, Susan Cooper, Helen Dunmore, Stephen Fry, Neil Gaiman, Elizabeth Garner, Paul Kingsnorth, Katherine Langrish, Helen Macdonald, Robert Macfarlane, Gregory Maguire, Neel Mukherjee, Philip Pullman, and many, many more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citethe-wicked-boy-the-mystery-of-a-victorian-child-murderercite-by-kate-summerscalehttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq8663131qryctibib3c20irn61026100qrytextthe20wicked20boy203a20the20mystery20of20a20victorian20child20murderer&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8663131?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(61026100)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20wicked%20boy%20%3A%20the%20mystery%20of%20a%20Victorian%20child%20murderer&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The wicked boy: the mystery of a Victorian child murderer&lt;/cite&gt; by Kate Summerscale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8663131?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(61026100)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20wicked%20boy%20%3A%20the%20mystery%20of%20a%20Victorian%20child%20murderer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/the-wicked-boy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The wicked boy: the mystery of a Victorian child murderer by Kate Summerscale&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author of The Suspicions of Mr Whicher returns to Victorian crime. Early in the morning of Monday 8 July 1895, 13-year-old Robert Coombes and his 12-year-old brother Nattie set out from their small terraced house in East London to watch a cricket match at Lord’s. Their father had gone to sea the previous Friday, the boys told their neighbours, and their mother was visiting her family in Liverpool. Over the next ten days Robert and Nattie spent extravagantly, pawning their parents’ valuables to fund trips to the theatre and the seaside. But as the sun beat down on the Coombes house, a strange smell began to emanate from the building.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 10:06:50 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/new-suggestions/non-fiction/new-non-fiction-for-may-2016/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/new-suggestions/non-fiction/new-non-fiction-for-may-2016/</guid>
        
        
        <category>new-suggestions</category>
        
        <category>non-fiction</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New fiction for May 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/featured/featured-love-you-dead.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Love you dead by Peter James&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citelove-you-deadcite-by-peter-jameshttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq8675251qryctibib3c20irn60852680ampqrytextlove20you20dead&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8675251?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(60852680)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Love%20you%20dead&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Love you dead&lt;/cite&gt; by Peter James&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8675251?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(60852680)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Love%20you%20dead&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/love-you-dead.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Love you dead by Peter James&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another case for Detective Superintendent Roy Grace. We are already getting a waiting list for this one. An ugly duckling as a child, Jodie Bentley had two dreams in life - to be beautiful and rich. She’s achieved the first, with a little help from a plastic surgeon, and now she’s working hard on the second. Her philosophy on money is simple: you can either earn it or marry it. Marrying is easy, it’s getting rid of the husband afterwards that’s harder, that takes real skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citethe-lubetkin-legacycite-by-marina-lewyckahttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq8679165qryctibib3c20irn60675241ampqrytextthe20lubetkin20legacy&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8679165?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(60675241)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20Lubetkin%20legacy&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The Lubetkin legacy&lt;/cite&gt; by Marina Lewycka&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8679165?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(60675241)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20Lubetkin%20legacy&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/the-lubetkin-legacy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Lubetkin legacy by Marina Lewycka&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopeless failed actor Berthold is exactly the same age as George Clooney (they share a birthday), but still lives with his mum. When he realises at her deathbed that he may lose his mother’s lovely council flat, built in the 1960s by celebrated architect Lubetkin, he adopts the old lady in the hospital bed next door and takes her home to impersonate his mum. What could possibly go wrong?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citethe-sorcerers-daughtercite-by-terry-brookshttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq8682103qryctibib3c20irn9784404ampqrytextthe20sorcerer27s20daughter&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8682103?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(9784404)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20sorcerer%27s%20daughter&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The sorcerer’s daughter&lt;/cite&gt; by Terry Brooks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8682103?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(9784404)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20sorcerer%27s%20daughter&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/the-sorcerers-daughter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The sorcerer&#39;s daughter by Terry Brooks&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspiration for the MTV series, the world of Shannara is brimming with untold stories and unexplored territory. In this book Terry Brooks breaks new ground with a standalone adventure that’s sure to thrill veteran readers and newer converts alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citeravenspur-rise-of-the-tudorscite-by-conn-igguldenhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq8685632qryctibib3c20irn61599006ampqrytextravenspur203a20rise20of20the20tudors&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8685632?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(61599006)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Ravenspur%20%3A%20rise%20of%20the%20tudors&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ravenspur: rise of the tudors&lt;/cite&gt; by Conn Iggulden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8685632?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(61599006)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Ravenspur%20%3A%20rise%20of%20the%20tudors&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/ravenspur-rise-of-the-tudors.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ravenspur: rise of the tudors by Conn Iggulden&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fourth and final novel in Conn Iggulden’s epic ‘War of the Roses’ series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citeprivate-investigationscite-by-quintin-jardinehttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq8687262qryctibib3c20irn170822ampqrytextprivate20investigations&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8687262?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(170822)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Private%20investigations&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Private investigations&lt;/cite&gt; by Quintin Jardine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8687262?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(170822)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Private%20investigations&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/private-investigations.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Private investigations by Quintin Jardine&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Former Chief Constable Bob Skinner has seen a few crime scenes during his 30-year career. But few have affected him quite as much as the horrifying sight he finds in the back of a stolen car that collides with his own on the outskirts of Edinburgh. As his former colleagues investigate the mystery, Skinner is left to take on the unusual challenge of tracing a million-pound yacht, vanished from its mooring. And yet, as the body count rises, a link surfaces that could provide the key to both. And as discord spreads within the newly unified Police Scotland, it will soon become clear whether Skinner is on the side of the angels - or working against them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citestalkercite-by-lars-keplerhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq8691276qryctibib3c20irn13358ampqrytextstalker&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8691276?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(13358)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Stalker&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Stalker&lt;/cite&gt; by Lars Kepler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8691276?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(13358)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Stalker&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/stalker-lars-kepler.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stalker by Lars Kepler&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A video-clip is sent to the National Criminal Investigation Department. Someone has secretly filmed a woman through her window from the garden. The next day she is found dead after a frenzied knife-attack. The police receive a second film of another unknown woman. There is no way of identifying her before time runs out. This is the latest from the Swedish husband and wife writing team Alexander Ahndoril and Alexandra Coelho Ahndoril.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citewhen-i-was-invisiblecite-by-dorothy-koomsonhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq8703199qryctibib3c20irn61026027ampqrytextwhen20i20was20invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8703199?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(61026027)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=When%20I%20was%20invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;When I was invisible&lt;/cite&gt; by Dorothy Koomson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8703199?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(61026027)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=When%20I%20was%20invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/when-i-was-invisible.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;When I was invisible by Dorothy Koomson&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1988, two girls with identical names and the same love of ballet meet for the first time. They seem destined to be best friends forever and to become professional dancers. Years later, however, they have both been dealt so many cruel and unexpected blows that they walk away from each other into very different futures - one enters a convent, the other becomes a minor celebrity. Will these new, ‘invisible’ lives be the ones they were meant to live, or will they only find that kind of salvation when they are reunited 20 years later?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citethe-mandibles-a-family-2029-2047cite-by-lionel-shriverhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq8704280qryctibib3c20irn59643595ampqrytextthe20mandibles203a20a20family2c202029-2047&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8704280?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(59643595)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20Mandibles%20%3A%20a%20family%2C%202029-2047&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The Mandibles: a family, 2029-2047&lt;/cite&gt; by Lionel Shriver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8704280?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(59643595)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20Mandibles%20%3A%20a%20family%2C%202029-2047&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/the-mandibles-a-family.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Mandibles: a family, 2029-2047 by Lionel Shriver&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set in 2029. Darkly funny and unsettling novel with some outcomes that can almost be seen now. The Mandibles have been counting on a sizable fortune filtering down when their 97-year-old patriarch dies. Yet America’s soaring national debt has grown so enormous that it can never be repaid. Under siege on the currency markets, the dollar is in meltdown. A bloodless world war will wipe out the savings of millions of American families. Their inheritance turned to dust, each family member must contend with disappointment, and as the effects of the downturn start to hit, the challenge of survival. Recently wealthy Avery is petulant that she can’t buy olive oil, while her sister Florence is forced to absorb strays into her cramped household. As their father Carter fumes at having to care for his stepmother now that a nursing home is too expensive, his sister Nollie, an expat author, returns from abroad to a country that’s unrecognizable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citethe-hawkshead-hostagecite-by-rebecca-topehttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq8706430qryctibib3c20irn59109999ampqrytextthe20hawkshead20hostage&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8706430?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(59109999)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20Hawkshead%20hostage&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The Hawkshead hostage&lt;/cite&gt; by Rebecca Tope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8706430?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(59109999)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20Hawkshead%20hostage&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/the-hawkshead-hostage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Hawkshead hostage by Rebecca Tope&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Latest from the popular author of the ‘Cotswold mysteries’. Persimmon ‘Simmy’ Brown finds herself caught up in another murder investigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citethe-gustav-sonatacite-by-rose-tremainhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq8709161qryctibib3c20irn62076923ampqrytextthe20gustav20sonata&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8709161?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(62076923)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20Gustav%20sonata&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The Gustav sonata&lt;/cite&gt; by Rose Tremain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/8709161?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(62076923)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20Gustav%20sonata&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/the-gustav-sonata.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Gustav sonata by Rose Tremain&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, one that has been on most people’s must read lists for 2016, The latest Rose Tremain. It is the tutor who tells the young Gustav that he must try to be more like a coconut - that he needs a hard shell to protect the softness inside. This is what his native Switzerland has perfected - a shell to protect its neutrality, to keep its people safe. But his beloved friend, Anton, doesn’t want to be safe - a gifted pianist, he longs to make his mark on the world outside. On holiday one summer in Davos, the boys stumble across a remote building. Long ago, it was a TB sanitorium; now it is wrecked and derelict. Here, they play a game of life and death, deciding which of their imaginary patients must burn. It becomes their secret. ‘The Gustav Sonata’ begins in the 1930s, under the shadow of the Second World War, and follows the boys into maturity, and middle age, where their friendship is tested as never before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;citewar-factorycite-by-neal-l-asherhttpssuffolkspyduscoukcgi-binspydusexeenqopacbibenq15241466qryctibib3c20irn64110802qrytextwar20factory&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/15241466?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(64110802)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=War%20factory&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;War Factory&lt;/cite&gt; by Neal L Asher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/15241466?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(64110802)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=War%20factory&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/article/war-factory.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;War Factory by Neal L Asher&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast paced, high quality space opera. Thorvald Spear’s only goal is to get his revenge on the rogue artificial intelligence, Penny Royal. The AI apparently left him to die and killed thousands of his comrades in the process. But things aren’t as clear-cut as they seem. Can he truly rely on his own version of events? And has Penny Royal been meddling with his memories and his very identity?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 09:59:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/new-suggestions/fiction/new-fiction-for-may-2016/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/new-suggestions/fiction/new-fiction-for-may-2016/</guid>
        
        
        <category>new-suggestions</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mrs Hemingway by Naomi Wood</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/featured/featured-mrs-hemingway.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mrs Hemingway by Naomi Wood&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an intriguing novel centred on the four marriages of American author Ernest Hemingway. It’s an intense portrait of their lives together and an eloquent window into their world rather than a polemic: The reader may become frustrated and unsympathetic with their often heartless and selfish behaviour but in the end it’s a keen and honest observation of love, loneliness and obsession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As stated in the afterword, Mrs Hemingway is a work of fiction, but the prose is so good and the characters so vivid that it becomes as believable as a work of non-fiction. Largely structured around the beginning and end of each relationship, the novels first chapters are set in Antibes with Hemingway, his first wife Hadley and mistress Fife on holiday together. It’s a very clever and surprisingly enjoyable read and by the end it is very hard not be moved and hungry to learn more about these larger than life characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/20217733?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(32816157)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Mrs.%20Hemingway&quot;&gt;Order &lt;cite&gt;Mrs Hemingway&lt;/cite&gt; from our catalogue →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 09:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/new-suggestions/staff-picks/mrs-hemingway-by-naomi-wood/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/new-suggestions/staff-picks/mrs-hemingway-by-naomi-wood/</guid>
        
        
        <category>new-suggestions</category>
        
        <category>staff-picks</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet the author: Mary Beard</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/featured/featured-spqr.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SPQR&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mary Beard is Professor of Classics at the University of Cambridge, classics editor of &lt;cite&gt;The Times Literary Supplement&lt;/cite&gt; and author of the blog, &lt;cite&gt;A Don’s Life&lt;/cite&gt; which also appears in &lt;cite&gt;The Times&lt;/cite&gt;. Often described as Britain’s best-known classicist,  Mary’s latest book &lt;cite&gt;SPQR: a history of ancient Rome&lt;/cite&gt; is one of our most popular non-fiction titles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your latest book &lt;cite&gt;SPQR&lt;/cite&gt; is a big favourite here in Suffolk. What do you think it is about the Romans that continues to catch the public imagination?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am really pleased it is a favourite… More to do with the Romans than me I think. The Romans capture our imagination because they are so deeply embedded in our culture… Most of us know about how wicked many of the Roman Emperors were, but we say “I am Spartacus”, and we love &lt;cite&gt;Gladiator&lt;/cite&gt;. The Romans speak to our naughty side, but they also remind us of higher things: Civil liberties, Citizenship, Freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apart from your own books where would you recommend a new reader to start to read the classics?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Holland’s &lt;cite&gt;Rubicon&lt;/cite&gt; is great. A really good story of the most turbulent time of Rome. If you want to see how ancient myth works in the modern era, I recommend Helen Morales’ &lt;cite&gt;Very short introduction to Classical Mythology&lt;/cite&gt;, A great glimpse of why it all matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who were your literary heroes as you were growing up?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A difficult one. In fiction I have to confess I loved &lt;cite&gt;Jane Eyre&lt;/cite&gt;. All about how to be a woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is on your reading list at the moment?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Odd things. I am reading J Brotton’s book about the sale of King Charles I’s pictures and I am mugging up on Mexican Art (Yes!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Given a time machine and the ability to go backwards or forwards what date would you set the clock for and why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh dear. Can I please stay where I am?? I am really interested in Ancient Rome, but would hate to live there. And who knows what the future holds?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/11572742?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(49010840)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=SPQR%20%3A%20a%20history%20of%20ancient%20Rome&quot;&gt;Reserve &lt;cite&gt;SPQR: a history of ancient Rome&lt;/cite&gt; by Mary Beard from our catalogue.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 12:08:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/meet-the-author-mary-beard/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/meet-the-author-mary-beard/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reading Well for young people</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/featured/featured-reading-well-for-young-people.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Self-Esteem Team’s Guide to Sex, Drugs and WTFs?!! by The Self-Esteem Team, Mind Your Head by Juno Dawson and Blame My Brain: The Amazing Teenage Brain Revealed by Nicola Morgan&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://reading-well.org.uk/books/books-on-prescription/young-people-s-mental-health&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Reading Well&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt; have compiled a list of 35 recommended books on the topic of young people’s mental health. You can borrow these books from our libraries or from our eLibrary service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;general&quot;&gt;General&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2484221?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(53719364)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Stuff%20that%20sucks%20%3A%20accepting%20what%20you%20can%27t%20change%20and%20committing%20to%20what%20you%20can&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Stuff That Sucks: Accepting What You Can’t Change and Committing to What You Can&lt;/cite&gt; by Ben Sedley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2484664?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(57962502)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Mind%20your%20head&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Mind Your Head&lt;/cite&gt; by Juno Dawson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/3535900?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(55306896)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20Self-Esteem%20Team%27s%20guide%20to%20sex%2C%20drugs%20%26%20WTFs%3F!!&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The Self-Esteem Team’s Guide to Sex, Drugs and WTFs?!!&lt;/cite&gt; by The Self-Esteem Team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2485524?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(698397)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Blame%20my%20brain%20%3A%20the%20amazing%20teenage%20brain%20revealed&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Blame My Brain: The Amazing Teenage Brain Revealed&lt;/cite&gt; by Nicola Morgan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2485956?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(1333080)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Quiet%20the%20mind&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Quiet the Mind&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/cite&gt; by Matthew Johnstone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2486359?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(47356484)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=I%27ll%20give%20you%20the%20sun&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;I’ll Give You the Sun&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/cite&gt; by Jandy Nelson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2486629?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(20248644)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Kite%20spirit&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Kite Spirit&lt;/cite&gt; by Sita Brahmachari&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2487044?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(1092139)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=House%20of%20windows&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;House of Windows&lt;/cite&gt; by Alexia Casale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2490757?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(235225)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Every%20day&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Every Day&lt;/cite&gt; by David Levithan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;adhd&quot;&gt;ADHD&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/7429915?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(63831256)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Putting%20on%20the%20brakes%20%3A%20understanding%20and%20taking%20control%20of%20your%20ADD%20or%20ADHD&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Putting on the Brakes: Understanding and Taking Control of Your ADD or ADHD&lt;/cite&gt; by Patricia Quinn and Judith Stern&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;anxiety-worry-and-panic&quot;&gt;Anxiety, worry and panic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2494215?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(1241917)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=My%20anxious%20mind%20%3A%20a%20teen%27s%20guide%20to%20managing%20anxiety%20and%20panic&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;My Anxious Mind: A Teen’s Guide to Managing Anxiety and Panic&lt;/cite&gt; by Michael Tompkins and Katherine Martinez&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://suffolklibraries.lib.overdrive.com/11CAD647-0210-4285-BF0F-8B900F964402/10/50/en/ContentDetails.htm?id=3405E646-659F-4030-915F-F429D55BFCFA&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The Anxiety Survival Guide for Teens: CBT Skills to Overcome Fear, Worry and Panic&lt;/cite&gt; by Jennifer Shannon&lt;/a&gt; (eBook)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://suffolklibraries.lib.overdrive.com/11CAD647-0210-4285-BF0F-8B900F964402/10/50/en/ContentDetails.htm?id=848B4D8B-3479-4E60-976A-213BFEB78BD3&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The Shyness and Social Anxiety Workbook for Teens&lt;/cite&gt; by Jennifer Shannon&lt;/a&gt; (eBook)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2491887?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(704656)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20perks%20of%20being%20a%20wallflower&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The Perks of Being a Wallflower&lt;/cite&gt; by Stephen Chbosky&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;autism-and-asperger-syndrome&quot;&gt;Autism and Asperger syndrome&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2491489?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(20750620)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20reason%20I%20jump&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The Reason I Jump&lt;/cite&gt; by Naoki Higashida&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2490097?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(1603771)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Freaks%2C%20geeks%20and%20Asperger%20syndrome%20%3A%20a%20user%20guide%20to%20adolescence&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Freaks, Geeks and Asperger Syndrome: A User’s Guide to Adolescence&lt;/cite&gt; by Luke Jackson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2491190?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(133590)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20curious%20incident%20of%20the%20dog%20in%20the%20night-time&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The Curious Incident of the Dog in the Night-Time&lt;/cite&gt; by Mark Haddon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;body-image-and-eating-disorders&quot;&gt;Body image and eating disorders&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2494855?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(42024786)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Can%20I%20tell%20you%20about%20eating%20disorders%3F%20%3A%20a%20guide%20for%20friends%2C%20family%20and%20professionals&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Can I Tell You About Eating Disorders?&lt;/cite&gt; by Bryan Lask and Lucy Watson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/3555535?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(34004251)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Banish%20your%20body%20image%20thief%20%3A%20a%20cognitive%20behavioural%20therapy%20workbook%20on%20building%20positive%20body%20image%20for%20young%20people&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Banish Your Body Image Thief: a cognitive behavioural therapy workbook on building positive body image for young people&lt;/cite&gt; by Kate Collins-Donnelly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2493423?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(891186)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Tyranny&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Tyranny&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/cite&gt; by Lesley Fairfield&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bullying&quot;&gt;Bullying&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2495226?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(14734474)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Bullies%2C%20cyberbullies%20and%20frenemies&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Teen Life Confidential: Bullies, Cyberbullies and Frenemies&lt;/cite&gt; by Michele Elliott&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://suffolklibraries.lib.overdrive.com/11CAD647-0210-4285-BF0F-8B900F964402/10/50/en/ContentDetails.htm?id=8F6151FA-91CF-4F08-AD79-ECD78D60E59E&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Vicious: True Stories by Teens about Bullying&lt;/cite&gt; edited by Hope Vanderberg (eBook)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;confidence-and-self-esteem&quot;&gt;Confidence and self-esteem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2495422?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(36215422)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Banish%20your%20self-esteem%20thief%20%3A%20a%20cognitive%20behavioural%20therapy%20workbook%20on%20building%20positive%20self-esteem%20for%20young%20people&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Banish Your Self-Esteem Thief: A Cognitive Behavioural Therapy Workbook on Building Positive Self-Esteem for Young People&lt;/cite&gt; by Kate Collins-Donnelly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2490510?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(20247141)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Self%20esteem%20and%20being%20you&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Teen Life Confidential: Self-Esteem and Being You&lt;/cite&gt; by Anita Naik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2489537?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(28342)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Face&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Face&lt;/cite&gt; by Benjamin Zephaniah&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;depression&quot;&gt;Depression&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2494537?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(56500042)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Am%20I%20depressed%20and%20what%20can%20I%20do%20about%20it%3F%20%3A%20a%20CBT%20self-help%20guide%20for%20teenagers%20experiencing%20low%20mood%20and%20depression&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Am I Depressed and What Can I Do About it?&lt;/cite&gt; by Shirley Reynolds and Monika Parkinson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2489084?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(1010207)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=I%20had%20a%20black%20dog&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;I Had a Black Dog&lt;/cite&gt; by Matthew Johnstone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2494712?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(46653016)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Can%20I%20tell%20you%20about%20depression%3F%20%3A%20a%20guide%20for%20friends%2C%20family%20and%20professionals&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Can I Tell You About Depression?&lt;/cite&gt; by Christopher Dowrick and Susan Martin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mood-swings&quot;&gt;Mood swings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/12495881?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(902846)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Don%27t%20let%20your%20emotions%20run%20your%20life%20for%20teens%20%3A%20dialectical%20behavior%20therapy%20skills%20for%20helping%20teens%20manage%20mood%20swings%2C%20control%20angry%20outbursts%2C%20and%20get%20along%20with%20others&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Don’t Let Your Emotions Run Your Life for Teens&lt;/cite&gt; by Sheri van Dijk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ocd&quot;&gt;OCD&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2492308?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(1610612)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Touch%20and%20go%20Joe%20%3A%20an%20adolescent%27s%20experience%20of%20OCD&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Touch and Go Joe&lt;/cite&gt; by Joe Wells&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2495709?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(1610882)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Breaking%20free%20from%20OCD%20%3A%20a%20CBT%20guide%20for%20young%20people%20and%20their%20families&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Breaking Free from OCD: A CBT Guide for Young People and their Families&lt;/cite&gt; by Jo Derisley, Isobel Heyman, Sarah Robinson, Cynthia Turner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2488833?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(47113609)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20unlikely%20hero%20of%20Room%2013B&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The Unlikely Hero of Room 13B&lt;/cite&gt; by Teresa Toten&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;self-harm&quot;&gt;Self-harm&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/3558207?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(60852793)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Truth%20About%20Self-harm%20%3A%20For%20Young%20People%20and%20Their%20Friends&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;The Truth About Self-Harm&lt;/cite&gt; by Celia Richardson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stress&quot;&gt;Stress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/3553959?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(60852794)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=Fighting%20invisible%20tigers%20%3A%20stress%20management%20for%20teens&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Fighting Invisible Tigers: A Stress Management Guide for Teens&lt;/cite&gt; by Earl Hipp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://suffolk.spydus.co.uk/cgi-bin/spydus.exe/ENQ/OPAC/BIBENQ/2487716?QRY=CTIBIB%3C%20IRN(38544638)&amp;amp;QRYTEXT=The%20teenage%20guide%20to%20stress&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Teenage Guide to Stress&lt;/cite&gt; by Nicola Morgan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 15:31:07 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/health/reading-well-for-young-people/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/health/reading-well-for-young-people/</guid>
        
        
        <category>health</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
