<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Your awesome title</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 16:25:41 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 16:25:41 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introducing Sarah, our new mental health and wellbeing coordinator</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My name is Sarah and I’m the new &lt;a href=&quot;http://suffolklibraries.co.uk/community-services/mental-health-information-services&quot;&gt;mental health and wellbeing&lt;/a&gt; coordinator for Suffolk Libraries. Here is a little bit about me to introduce myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years I’ve worked in an NHS Mental Health Trust, supporting and coordinating various projects around health and wellbeing, including service redesign, research, writing grant applications and evaluations. I also coordinated a Wellbeing programme called Bounce!, which sat within a Big Lottery Funded portfolio in the East of England.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bounce! provided wellbeing workshops and support to over 8,500 people across Essex, Suffolk and Norfolk and was designed to help people in learning about wellbeing, how wellbeing is different for each person and also to look at making small changes to improve their resilience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The programme worked with a wide range of community groups and organisations, as well as offering specific skill- building workshops to Looked After Children, Armed Forces Families and those who use foodbanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this time I developed a passion for working within the community and I especially enjoy working towards improving health and wellbeing. I love nothing more than working with people to problem solve in services, create new projects and engage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a time where health services are facing cuts and increasing pressure to deliver more, I believe the community is a great place to start when it comes to empowering and encouraging people to improve their wellbeing, become more resilient, and have the confidence and knowledge of where to go for help when it is needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love to be creative and in my spare time I can often be found surrounded by arts and crafts items, baking cakes or with my nose in a good book! Reading has always been a big part of my life – I usually have a few books on the go and I’m always adding to my ‘To read’ pile. Growing up I adored Roald Dahl (Especially &lt;cite&gt;George’s Marvellous Medicine&lt;/cite&gt; and &lt;cite&gt;Matilda&lt;/cite&gt;), R. L. Stine’s &lt;cite&gt;Goosebumps&lt;/cite&gt; and of course, the &lt;cite&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/cite&gt; series – which I still enjoy as an adult! These days I like to read as many different genres and authors as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m thrilled to be a part of Suffolk Libraries and I hope to continue the excellent reputation the lovely David Grimmer built for this valuable service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please don’t hesitate to contact me at sarah.lungley@suffolklibraries.co.uk if there is anything I can do to help or if you have any questions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 10:59:08 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2016/04/07/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2016/04/07/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Suffolk Libraries – an update on our budget for 2016/2017</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Suffolk County Council approved their budget proposals at February’s full council meeting which included a reduction to the library service budget of £650,000 over two years. Suffolk Libraries Board have since agreed to the reduction of £350,000 for 2016/17.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The further savings needed to meet our new budget for 2016/17 should not have any significant impact on the frontline library service this year and Suffolk Libraries is committed to not closing any libraries during the life of the current contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are still in discussions about the further saving for 2017/18 but will continue to work closely and positively with the county council throughout the year and will keep everyone informed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may have seen from last week’s national and regional media coverage, many libraries have closed across the country but the story in Suffolk is still a very positive one where all 44 libraries have remained open and with the support of our community groups, Suffolk Libraries has even been able to introduce new services and provides an increasingly diverse range of services and activities. For example – the Community Group in Beccles is funding an increase in opening hours at their library from April 2016 and the community groups at Kesgrave and Glemsford are supporting refurbishment work at their libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always we are grateful to all our customers and community groups for their ongoing support of our library service.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 10:59:08 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2016/04/06/suffolk-libraries-an-update-on-our-budget-for-20162017.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2016/04/06/suffolk-libraries-an-update-on-our-budget-for-20162017.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Felixstowe Library’s Golden Anniversary</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This April marks 50 years since &lt;a href=&quot;http://suffolklibraries.co.uk/branches/felixstowe-library&quot;&gt;Felixstowe Library&lt;/a&gt; opened for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The library will be marking this milestone in several ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The celebrations will kick off with a visit from Felixstowe Community Choir on Saturday 23 April from 11am to 12noon. This is also the same day as World Book night. This very special one-off performance is a real treat as the choir are in great demand. On the day the library will also be decorated with memorabilia from 1966 with staff dressed in clothes from the 1960’s and music from the same era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be a 1966 quiz running throughout the month. It costs £1 to enter and any money raised will help to support the library. The winners will be announced on 30 April and there are great prizes to be won.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look out for a special exhibition about the history of the library and if you want to contribute there’s also a celebration box in the library for anyone to post their memories, photos or comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Felixstowe Library is also hosting an afternoon with local crime author Alison Bruce on Saturday 30 April at 2pm with doors opening at 1.30pm. She will be talking about her Cambridge-based crime novels and will be signing copies of her books. Tickets are £5 and must be booked in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent comment from a customer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Felixstowe Library is a fantastic asset to our local community. The staff are very knowledgeable and helpful. The range of groups/activities for ALL ages and sections of the community is outstanding.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 10:59:08 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2016/04/05/felixstowe-librarys-golden-anniversary.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2016/04/05/felixstowe-librarys-golden-anniversary.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
